<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="alfheim">Alfheim is the closest place to Asgard. This region is inhabited by light fairies and are believed to be the most beautiful creatures.\n\n\nLight fairies are nature gods who provide fertility and sometimes also help humans. They also often provide inspiration through art and music. The Vanir god Freyr is said to be the ruler of Alfheim.</string>
    <string name="asgard">In the world of Norse mythology, precisely in the high sky is Asgard, the home of the gods. Odin is the ruler of Asgard. Odin married Frigg and made them both king and queen of Asgard.\n\n\nThere is the Bifrost bridge, which is a rainbow bridge that connects Asgard with Midgard. In Asgard there is also Odin\'s throne called Hildskjalf where Odin can see the whole world from his throne.</string>
    <string name="mainmenucap">(Aesir gods and goddesses)</string>
    <string name="ashelm">Ash and Embla were the first humans – male and female, respectively – created in Norse mythology.\n\n\nNot long after the world itself was created, Odin walked along the shore of one of the new lands. With him were two other gods his brothers Vili and Ve.\n\n\nThe three gods found two tree trunks, perhaps pieces of driftwood, lying on the beach. They were shaped like men and women, but they were lifeless and helpless. So the three gods decided to give them what they lacked and make them real humans. Odin breathed the breath of life into them, while the two gods provided inspired mental activity, healthy skin, and the ability to speak, hear, and see. They dressed them in appropriate clothing and named the man ash and the woman Embla/elm. Ash and Embla were then given Midgard, a world of human civilization, to live in. They became the father and mother of the entire human species.</string>
    <string name="audhumla">Audumla or Audhumla is a primeval cow. Audumla was born from the meeting of hot lava and ice water at Ginnungagap.\nA cow named Audhumla and a giant named Ymir, these two creatures were the first to appear in the world.\nAn early giant, Ymir (Aurgelmir), lived by drinking Audumla\'s milk. Audumla was also a source of milk for Ymir\'s six-headed sons.\n\nAudumla itself obtains food by licking rocks. Audumla licked it until the rock formed a creature and became Buri, a god who was the grandfather of the three Aesir gods, namely Odin, Vili and Ve.</string>
    <string name="baldur">Baldur is a Norse god of the Aesir tribe with unmatched beauty and wisdom who resolves disputes between humans and gods. His death as a result of Loki\'s deception is one of the central stories of Norse mythology.\n\n\none of the Aesir gods. He was the son of Odin and Frigg, husband of the unknown goddess Nanna, and father of the god Forseti.\nHe is loved by all the gods, goddesses and more physical beings. So handsome, graceful, and cheerful was he that he literally radiated light.\n\n\nWhen Baldur began to dream of his death, Frigg went to everyone in the world and secured from each of them an oath not to harm her son. Confident in Baldur\'s toughness, the gods amused themselves by throwing weapons and whatever random objects they could find at Baldur and watching them bounce off him, leaving him completely unharmed.\n\n\nLoki, the cunning trickster of the gods, senses an opportunity to do evil. He asked Frigg if she had neglected anything in her efforts to obtain the oath. He casually replied that he thought the mistletoe was too small and harmless to warrant such a promise. Loki immediately made a spear out of mistletoe and convinced the blind god Hodr to throw it at Baldur. The projectile penetrates the god, and he falls dead.\n\n\nThe suffering gods then suggest that one of them should go to the underworld to see if there is any way that Baldur can be taken from the clutches of the goddess of death, Hel. Hermod, one of Odin\'s many sons, agreed to make this journey, and, mounting Odin\'s horse Sleipnir, he rode the world tree until he came to its dark, damp roots, where Hel\'s abode lay. When he arrived, he found his brother, pale and grim, sitting in the seat of honor next to Hel. Hermod begs the terrible goddess to release Baldur, and after much persuasion, she replies that she will hand him over if and only if everything in the world will weep for Baldur – to prove, in other words, that he is as universally loved as Hermod. claimed.\n\n\nThe whole world indeed wept for the benevolent son of Odin – all but one creature. The giant ökk, generally assumed to be Loki in disguise, callously refuses to take action that would secure Baldur\'s return. And Baldur is destined to remain with Hel in her joyless realm.</string>
    <string name="bestla">Bestla is the giant daughter of the ice giant Bolthor. Bestla became the wife of an early god named Bor, son of Buri. She is the mother of the three Aesir gods, namely Odin, Vili and Ve.</string>
    <string name="bifrost">The Bifrost is a rainbow bridge connecting Asgard, the world of the Aesir divine tribe, with Midgard, the world of humanity. The Bifrost is guarded by the ever-vigilant god Heimdall. During Ragnarok, the giants will break through Heimdall\'s defenses and cross the bridge to invade Asgard and kill the gods.</string>
    <string name="bor">Bor or Bur is a giant ancient god. He was the son of the giant Buri. He likely looked more like a god than a giant. Bori married the ice giant Bestla and became the father of the first three Aesir gods, namely Odin, Vili (Hoenir) and Ve.</string>
    <string name="bragi">Bragi is a wise and learned poet from Valhalla, the majestic hall of the god Odin. he who worships the einherjar, the dead who live in Valhalla, and welcomes recently deceased heroes into their midst. he has runes carved into his tongue.\n\n\nBragi was originally the ninth century historical poet Bragi Boddason. His poetry was so beautiful and moving that later generations imagined that, after his death, Odin appointed him court poet of Valhalla. After all, the elite army of warriors, kings, and others favored by Odin needed elite bards to sing of their countless exploits.\n\n\nThe Old Norse writers of the Christian Middle Ages took this a step further and depicted Bragi as a god of poetry. He was said to be the husband of the goddess Idun, whose fruit ensured the continued immortality of the gods.\n\n\nHowever, this appears to be a misunderstanding on the part of the late author, and there is no evidence that Bragi was ever actually worshiped as a god while pre-Christian Norse religion was still a living tradition</string>
    <string name="buri">Buri is the ancestral giant of the gods. Buri was created from a rock or ice that was licked by a giant ancient cow, Audumla, to form itself. Buri was Bor\'s father and grandfather of the first three Aesir gods, namely Odin, Vili and Ve.\n\n\nIt is not completely clear whether Buri was a god or a giant.</string>
    <string name="dagr">Dagr is the divine personification of the day/sun in Norse mythology. Dagr is declared the son of the god Dellingr and is associated with the bright-maned horse Skinfaxi, who represents the day for mankind. Depending on manuscript variations, Dagr was the son of Dellingr by Nótt, personified night, or Jörð, personified Earth. Otherwise, Dagr appears as a common noun meaning (day).</string>
    <string name="dwaft">The dwarves live underground in Svartalfheim, a place that might be thought to be a labyrinthine complex of mines and forges.\n\n\nDwarves are most often known as highly skilled blacksmiths and craftsmen. Among the many irreplaceable treasures created by them are: Mjollnir, Thor\'s hammer; Gleipnir, the chain that binds the wolf Fenrir when all other shackles fail; Skidbladnir, Freyr\'s ship and always has a good wind; Gungnir, Odin\'s spear; Draupnir, Odin\'s ring; Brisingamen, Freya\'s magnificent necklace; and the long golden hair of Sif, Thor\'s wife. They are also very knowledgeable, wise, and magically powerful. They turn to stone when exposed to sunlight.\n\n\nThe four dwarves, Austri, Vestri, Nordri, and Sudri (East, West, North, and South) hold up the four corners of the sky, proving their colossal power.\n\n\nThe lines between dwarves, elves, and dead humans are very blurred. Dwarves are sometimes called black elves, and in some cases they are depicted as dead or resembling human corpses.</string>
    <string name="fenrir">Fenrir is the giant wolf child of Loki and the giant Angerboda. Other names for Fenrir are Fenris, Fenrisúlfr, and Vanargand (wand of hope).\n\n\nFenrir grew so large so quickly that the gods became afraid. The gods pretended to play a game to bind the wolf, to see if Fenrir could break free. Fenrir agrees to play if someone is willing to put their hand in his mouth. Only the god of war, Tyr, dared to put his hand on Fenrir\'s mouth.\n\n\nThe gods found that nothing could bind Fenrir, until they obtained a powerful silver band called Gleipnir, made by the dwarves. This tape is made from the sounds of cat steps, women\'s beards, fish breath, and bird spit. When Fenrir was unable to free himself from this bondage, he realized that he had been deceived. In response, Fenrir bit Tyr\'s hand until it broke off. That\'s why Tyr is known as the One-Armed God.\n\n\nWhen Ragnarok began, Fenrir was free from his shackles. He then joined the giants and other monsters in the war against the gods. Fenrir fights against Odin. He managed to kill and eat Odin. Vidar, Odin\'s son, was angry and avenged his father\'s death by tearing Fenrir\'s jaw with his bare hands.\n\n\nAccording to Voluspa, Fenrir is the parent of another giant wolf, namely Moongarm, which is the wolf that swallowed the moon in Ragnarok. Moongram\'s mother is a female troll who lives in the Iron Forest, called Iarnvidiur.</string>
    <string name="forseti">Forseti is the son of Baldr and his wife Nanna, Forseti\'s expertise is mediation and law.\n\n\nHe became the inspiration for the ‘law speaker’, or logsogumaor in Old Norse, who was the head of the Scandinavian ping, or panel of judges.\nLegal speakers act as judges and decide disputes in accordance with the law.\n\n\nHe decides both the disputes between the gods and the thorny disputes among men.\n\n\nNo one who came to him for justice went home dissatisfied.\n\n\nThe hall is called Glitnir or shining because its silver roof and golden pillars radiate light for miles.\nHis symbol is the golden ax he carries.</string>
    <string name="freyvanir">Freyr was one of the most revered and revered gods among the Norse and other Germanic peoples. One Old Norse poem calls it (the most important of the gods and hated by none). The reasons for this are not difficult to understand; their well-being and prosperity depended on his benevolence, which specifically manifested itself in sexual and ecological fertility, bountiful harvests, wealth, and peace. His role in providing health and abundance is often symbolized by his fylgja, the Gullinborsti (Golden-haired) boar, and by his large, erect phallus.\n\n\nSo, it is not surprising that Freyr is often the recipient of sacrifices on various occasions, such as wedding blessings or harvest celebrations. During the harvest festival, the sacrifice traditionally takes the form of his beloved animal, the wild boar.\n\n\nHis father was Njord, and his mother was Njord\'s unnamed sister (possibly Nerthus). Freyr himself has been the lover of many goddesses and giants, including his own sister, Freya.\n\n\nApparently incest was a common and acceptable practice among the Vanir (though certainly not among historical Germanic peoples).\n\n\nFreyr\'s residence is Alfheim, the homeland of the elves.\nAnother of Freyr\'s signature items was his ship, the Skíðblaðnir, which always had a good wind and could be folded up and carried in a small bag. Its name, meaning Assembled from Thin Pieces of Wood, suggests that it served as a mythological archetype of a ship built for specific ritual purposes and never intended to be seaworthy. We know from archaeological evidence that ships played a major role in the pre-Christian religious rituals of the Germanic peoples, which closely matches the major role played by ships in the Bronze and Iron Ages, especially among the Scandinavians.\n\n\nOn land, Freyr traveled in a chariot drawn by wild boars. This is another mythological feature reflected in historical rituals. We know from medieval Icelandic sources that priests and/or priestesses of Freyr traveled throughout the country in chariots containing statues of the god.\nDuring Ragnarok, Freyr and the giant Surt are destined to destroy each other.</string>
    <string name="freya">Freya is one of the prominent goddesses in Norse mythology. He was a member of the Vanir tribe of gods, but became an honorary member of the Aesir gods after the Aesir-Vanir War. His father is Njord. His mother is unknown, but could be Nerthus. Frey is his older brother. Her husband, named Odr in Old Norse literature, was of course none other than Odin, and, therefore, Freya was ultimately identified with Odin\'s wife Frigg.\n\n\nFreya was renowned for her predilection for love, fertility, beauty and fine possessions – and, because of these predilections, she was considered the party girl of the Aesir. Loki accused Freya of sleeping with all the gods and elves, including her brother.\nHe is certainly a passionate seeker of pleasure and thrill, but he is more than that.\n\n\nFreya is the archetype of the völva, a professional or semiprofessional practitioner of seidr, the most organized form of Norse magic. It was he who first brought this art to the gods, and, by extension, to humans as well. Given his skill in controlling and manipulating the desires, health, and prosperity of others, he is a being of almost unmatched knowledge and power.\n\n\nFreya presided over Folkvang\'s afterlife. She chose half of the warriors killed in battle to live there.\n\n\nFreya the Volvo\n\n\nSeidr is a form of pre-Christian Norse magic and shamanism that involves discerning the course of fate and working within its structure to bring about change, often by symbolically weaving new events into existence. This power could potentially be used for anything imaginable, and examples covering almost the entire range of the human condition can be found in Old Norse literature.\n\n\nIn the Viking Age, the völva was an itinerant soothsayer and wizard who traveled from town to town performing assigned seidr acts in exchange for lodging, food, and often other forms of compensation as well. Like other north Eurasian shamans, his social status was highly ambiguous – he was alternately exalted, feared, longed for, propitiated, celebrated, and derided.\n\n\nFreya occupying this role among the gods is stated directly in the Ynglinga Saga, and indirect hints are dropped elsewhere in the Eddas and sagas. For example, in one story, Freya has an eagle feather that allows its bearer to change its form into an eagle.</string>
    <string name="frigg">Frigg is known as Odin\'s wife, Frigg was a powerful member of the Aesir pantheon and queen of all the Norse gods. Frigg holds power over many areas of life, and is associated with fertility, marriage and home, love and sexuality, and wisdom and prophecy.\nHistorically, most people consider Frigg to be an aspect of Freya, the goddess of the Vanir tribe, due to her basic characteristics being very similar to Frigg\'s.\n\n\nLike Freya, Frigg was a völva, or practitioner of the magical arts of seidr, and attempted to predict or change the future through ritual. While the two goddesses are often presented as separate deities, they likely evolved from a single deity whose personality oscillated violently enough to warrant separate identities. Freya, for example, was known for her sexual indulgence and promiscuity; Frigg, meanwhile, was more conservative in her sexual morality.\n\n\nAttribute\n\n\nAs Odin\'s wife, Frigg was the undisputed queen of the Norse gods. In art from the nineteenth and early twentieth centuries, Frigg was often depicted sitting on a throne or holding a commanding pose.\n\n\nFrigg lived in Fensalir, a watery realm that may have taken the form of a marsh, marsh, or wetland. He had a gray box called an eski, which the goddess Fulla brought him; the contents of the box are unknown. He is also known to possess a set of eagle feathers that the gods, especially Loki, use to shapeshift into bird form.\nOdin and Frigg, sat in Hlithskjolf—Odin\'s throne room—from where they could observe all the worlds simultaneously.</string>
    <string name="gamr">A Garm (Old Norse Garmr, whose meaning/etymology is unknown) is a dog or wolf associated with the underworld and destructive powers. the destruction of the cosmos and its sinking back into chaos. One of the other events that the herald of Ragnarok speaks of is the escape of the wolf Fenrir, who had been bound by the gods and abandoned in a remote swamp so that he would not devour the cosmos. The two images of a bound wolf breaking loose at the same time made one wonder whether Fenrir and Garm were ultimately the same figure or not.\n\n\nThis interpretation is supported by the fact that, as the god and fighting force of chaos during Ragnarok, the god Tyr is said to engage Garm in single combat. Since Tyr had previously tricked Fenrir into letting himself be bound in an unbreakable chain, and since Fenrir had bitten the god\'s hand in the process, it makes sense that the two would have a grudge against each other, which in turn makes it likely that Tyr\'s wolves will fight during Ragnarok not another is Fenrir.</string>
    <string name="gefjun">Gefjun is a goddess in Norse mythology. She is the goddess of agriculture and fertility in Norse mythology. One of the famous stories involving Gefjun is about the creation of the island of Zealand (Sjælland), which is the largest island in modern Denmark.\n\nAccording to Norse mythology, Odin, the leader of the gods, asked Gefjun to create an island from the Swedish mainland to become a new home for the Danish people. Gefjun agreed to Odin\'s request and went to the Swedish mainland with a large rotating disk. He used it to scratch and lift large tracts of land from the Swedish mainland and tow them into the sea. This land became the island of Zealand, while the lake formed from the former land became Lake Roskilde in Denmark.\n\nGefjun is often depicted as a powerful and powerful goddess associated with fertility, agriculture and the land. It is also often identified with the symbol of the yoni, which is a symbol of fertility in Norse mythology.</string>
    <string name="ginung">Ginnungagap is a bottomless abyss that existed before the creation of the cosmos, and where the cosmos will collapse once again during Ragnarok, giinungagap (emptiness/nothingness), which is a huge abyss-like shape flanked by the 2 worlds of Niflheim (the always cold and dark world) which everything froze… and Muspelheim (hot world) because of the sparks of fire and flowing lava… ginungagap became a meeting place for 2 temperatures between muspelheim and niflheim... over time, the effect of the meeting of the two temperatures, the beginning of life emerged\n\na wide abyss in outer space, so wide that there was no sound, light, or anything living or non-living within it, a truly empty place. From the origin of the word, Gap has the same meaning as that used in English today, namely gap, while the meaning of the word Ginnung means \"magically charged\" (Magic Field or Energy Field).\n\nGinnungagap the place facing north will be colder, filled with icebergs and nothing grows there, while inside it splashes water and blows wind, and in the south it is lit by sparks and sparkling masses flowing from Muspelheim.</string>
    <string name="gullveig">Gullveig is a wizard and fortune teller who has a great love and lust for gold. He didn\'t talk about anything else when he visited the Aesir. They listened with hatred and finally thought the world would be better off without him so they threw him into the fire. He burned to death, but emerged from the fire unscathed. Three times he was burned, and three times he was born again.\n\n\nWhen the Vanir learned about how the Aesir treated Gullveig, they became furious. They swore revenge and began preparing for war. The Aesir heard about this and moved against the Vanir. This is the world\'s first war. For a long time the battle raged to and fro, with neither side gaining much ground. Eventually the gods grew tired of war and began to talk about peace. Both sides vowed to coexist in peace.\n\n\nGullveig is also known as Heid (the glittering one). She may have been the goddess Freya, who also loved gold in various myths.</string>
    <string name="heimdal">Heimdal is one of the Aesir gods and the ever-vigilant guardian of the gods\' stronghold, Asgard.\n\n\nHis residence is called Himinbjörg (Heavenly Cliff, meaning a high place ideal for a fortress), located at the top of the Bifrost, the rainbow bridge leading to Asgard. He needs less sleep than a bird. His eyesight was so sharp that he could see hundreds of miles during the day or night, and his hearing was so sharp that he could hear the grass growing on the ground and the wool growing on the sheep. Here he looked and listened, while preparing the trumpet Gjallarhorn (Thundering Trumpet), which he sounded as the intruder approached.\n\n\nDuring Ragnarok, the gods will know that their end is near when they hear the terrible call of the Gjallarhorn signaling the imminent arrival of giants, who will cross the rainbow bridge to invade Asgard and kill the gods. The unfaithful Loki, the mortal enemy of Heimdall, will be with them. Loki and Heimdall will kill each other as the world burns and sinks into the sea.\n\n\nHeimdall himself, like many Norse gods, was the son of Odin. In a feat possible for gods but not for biological beings, he was born from no less than nine mothers.</string>
    <string name="hel">Hel is a creature from Norse mythology (Old Norse) in the form of a female giant who has power over many dead people. The name Hel, which means hidden, is closely related to the underworld and the dead who are hidden or buried in the ground.\n\n\nHel is the daughter of the god Loki and the giant Angrboda. His kingdom lay down and to the north in what was once called Niflheim, which means the world of darkness. Hel is associated with a dog named Garmr and a raven. Sometimes it is also affiliated with the Hagalaz Rune stone. This makes him part of a dangerous and disreputable family.\n\n\nHel is generally depicted as greedy, rude and cruel, and most indifferent to the good of the living and the dead.\n\n\nHel\'s father, Loki, was the god Panipu, while her mother, Angrboda, was a giant. Hel was born from the bones of half of her body exposed. When Hel was born, disease first came into the world.\n  Loki has three children, namely the wolf Fenrir, the sea serpent Jörmungandr and Hel who is his only daughter. Hel grew up with her two siblings in the land of giants, namely Jötunheimr to Odin. the ruler of the Aesir decided they should stay in Asgard where their father came from. However, while in Asgard, the other Norse gods felt uncomfortable with Hel\'s appearance. Odin finally told Hel to leave and then gave her the world of Niflheim which is one of the nine realms of the cosmic ash tree Yggdrasil. Niflheim exists under the roots of the world tree Yggdrasil. There, Hel became queen of the dead.</string>
    <string name="helheim">Helheim is the bleakest place in Norse mythology. This place is a place where thieves, murderers and people who are considered dishonorable live their afterlife.\n\n\nThis place is led by Hel. Anyone who arrives at this place will never feel joy or happiness again. However, in the event of Ragnarok, Hel will use all these dead people to attack Asgard and it will be the end of the world.\n\n\nAnother typical account is Hermod\'s journey to Hel to try to retrieve Baldur, who had been killed by Loki. While the account comes exclusively from Snorri, it fits well enough with other parts of this genre of underground travel narrative, both in its overall form and in small details, that we can be sure that Snorri relied on older or now lost sources. for us. The relevant part of the story goes like this:\n\n\nThe god Hermod departed from Asgard, the heavenly stronghold of the gods, on Sleipnir, Odin\'s horse. He descended the trunk of Yggdrasil, the great tree that formed the central axis of the cosmos. For nine nights, he rode through a deep valley, so pitch black he couldn\'t see the road. Finally, he came to a river, Gjöll (Loud Noise), which was spanned by a bridge called Gjallarbrú. On the bridge stands a giant, Móðguðr. The bridge guard wants to know why Hermod wants to cross, because he knows from his appearance that he is not dead. His answer, that he would look after Baldur, apparently satisfied the giant, who let him cross, telling him that Hel lay down and to the north ( niðr OK norðr ) from the bridge. When Hermod arrived at the fence around Hel, he jumped over the fence rather than through the gate. He then walked towards the hall of Hel (the goddess), where he found Baldur sitting in the seat of honor.</string>
    <string name="hvel">In Norse mythology, Hvergelmir is a major spring.\nthe location where the liquid from the antlers of the stag Eikþyrnir flows, and that the spring, from which all the water rises, is the source of many rivers.\n\n\nthat the spring is located in Niflheim, that it is one of the three main springs at the main root of the cosmic tree Yggdrasil (the other two being Urðarbrunnr and Mímisbrunnr), and that within the spring there are a large number of Níðhöggr snakes and dragons.</string>
    <string name="idun">The beautiful and enchanting Idun was the Norse goddess of youth and fertility. He plays a key role in Norse myth, rejuvenating the gods by giving them magic apples that reverse the effects of aging. He carries his apples in a box made of ash called an eski—along with the fruit, this box serves as one of his main symbols. She married Bragi, a skald (poet/poet) who narrated parts of the Lokasenna, of the Poetic Edda, and Skáldskaparmál of the Prose Edda.\n\n\nIdun holds the power to grant eternal youth and prevent old age. Her magic apples bestow the gift of eternal youth on those who eat them. Whenever the Norse gods began to feel the effects of aging, Idun would rejuvenate them with her apples.\n\n\nIdun\'s mythic tradition resides almost exclusively in the story of her abduction by the shape-shifting giant Thjazi. One day, Odin, Hoenir, and Loki traveled in the mountainous area of Asgard. When hungry travelers came across a herd of oxen, they slaughtered one and tried to cook it. However, every time they tried, the talking eagle used magic to prevent the fire from heating the juicy meat. The bird told the gods that if it did not receive its own share, no one would eat. The gods agreed to share their food, and the bird flew down to join them.\n\n\nWhen the eagle was close enough to touch, Loki grabbed a branch and attempted to attack it. However, Loki was too slow, and the bird caught the branch (which Loki was still holding) with its talons and flew away. When Loki begs to be released, the eagle reveals himself to be the giant Thjazi and demands that Idun and her magic apple be brought to him. Loki agrees to take it back, and the giant-turned-eagle returns it safely to the ground.\n\n\nWhen Loki returned home, he lured Idun into a dark forest by telling her that it was the location of rare and valuable fruit. However, instead of fruit, Idun found Thjazi waiting in his eagle form. The giant grabbed the young goddess and flew with her to her home in Jotunheimr.\n\n\nWithout the restorative power of the apple, the Norse gods withered and grew old: But the sir grew stiff at the loss of Idunn, and quickly they grew old and old, wrote Skáldskaparmál. 1 Loki is the last god seen with Idun, and the gods begin to question and threaten him for information. As their threats increase, Loki tells them that if they let him go and lends him Freya\'s falcon cloak, he will fly and return with the kidnapped goddess.\n\n\nWith cloak in hand, Loki flew to Jotunheimr where he found Idun alone in the halls of Thjazi. He turned it into a bean shape and flew away with it. Thjazi quickly discovered Loki\'s deception, and pursued the fleeing gods to the gates of Asgard. When the other gods saw Loki returning, they made a great fire that reached the sky. Loki pulled away from the fire at the last moment, but Thjazi wasn\'t so lucky. The giant eagle hurtled into hell before falling to the ground like a burning husk. “Then sir was near and killed Thjazi, the giant within sir\'s Gate, and the killing was very famous.</string>
    <string name="jormungand">Jormungand or Jormungandr, the World Serpent, the Midgard Serpent, is the son of Loki and the giant Angerboda. Jormungand symbolizes evil.\n\n\nJormungand is very dangerous. He can kill his prey by entangling it. Apart from that, the poison is also very deadly, even for gods. Jormungand is Thor\'s most dangerous enemy.\n\n\nTo confine the ever-growing Jormungand, Odin threw the snake into the sea. But Jormungand grew so big that his body completely encompassed the world.\n\n\nIn the first clash between Thor and Jormungand, Thor failed to kill the snake. Thor initially succeeded in trapping Jormungand like a fish. Then Thor tried to hit Jormungand\'s head with his hammer, Mjollnir. But the giant Hymir, frightened, cut Thor\'s fishing line so that Jormungand managed to escape.\n\n\nIn Ragnarok, Jormungand managed to escape from his underwater cage. Thor fought again with this snake and this time Thor succeeded in killing Jormungan with Mjollnir. But in the end, Thor also died due to Jormungand\'s poison</string>
    <string name="jotun">Jotunheim is the home of the giants. Apart from the giants and fire demons, the enemies of the gods are the giants who live in Jotunheim. Jotunheim is described as a deep and dark forest, mountain peaks where winter never leaves its grasp, and the same landscape does not friendly and gloomy.\n\n\nEven though there are forests, the land of Jotunheim is not fertile so the giants can only survive by preying on fish in the river.\n\n\nEven though it is said that the gods are mortal enemies of the giants, there is a story where there is a love affair between Odin and Thor with the giants and also Loki, who actually comes from Jotunheim but can live freely in Asgard.</string>
    <string name="loki">The great deceiver of the Norse pantheon, Loki is a cunning god known for his many schemes and tricks. As a shape-shifter, Loki\'s form is as diverse as the mischief he gets up to, including wealth, women, wisdom, and sheer delight in his deviousness. With Loki, appearances are never what they seem. While Loki\'s antics often involve the gods in difficult situations, his tricks often save them from tough times as well.\n\nA member of the Aesir god clan, Loki—along with Odin, Thor, and Freya—is one of the four ruling gods of Norse mythology. Although his mythology consistently overlaps with his divine peers, Loki differs from them in significant ways. Where Thor, Freya, and even Odin (a trickster himself) strive to enforce proper order among the gods, Loki\'s unpredictable behavior raises questions about his loyalty. For instance, it is predicted that during Ragnarök, Loki will fight alongside the jötnar against the gods.\n\nIn reality, Loki neither supports nor opposes the gods. Like other trickster figures in mythology, he is neither good nor evil, choosing instead to be a champion of chaos itself, a figure that tests boundaries and challenges conventions. His chaotic inconsistency reminds believers that the line between good and evil is far more blurred than they might assume.\n\nFor example, in the story of the Theft of Idun, Loki, due to his carelessness, ended up in the hands of an angry giant, Thiazi, who threatened to kill Loki unless he brought the goddess Idun to him. Loki complied to save his life, then found himself in an awkward position as the gods threatened him with death unless he saved Idun. He agreed to this request for the same basic motive, transforming into an eagle and bringing the goddess back to Asgard. In pursuit, Thiazi chased him desperately in the form of an eagle, but as he neared his target, the gods lit a fire around their fortress. The fire caught Thiazi and burned him to death, while Idun and Loki reached the hall of the gods safely. Loki eventually came to the aid of the gods, but only to rectify the disaster he had caused.\n\nAfter Thiazi\'s death, the giant\'s daughter, Skadi, arrived in Asgard to seek compensation for her father\'s murder. One of her demands was for the gods to make her laugh, something only Loki could accomplish. To achieve this, he tied one end of a cord to a goat\'s beard and the other to his testicles. Both he and the goat bellowed and screeched as one pulled in one direction and the other in another. Eventually, he fell into Skadi\'s lap, and the giantess couldn\'t help but laugh at the absurd spectacle. Here, Loki once again came to the aid of the gods, but by being silly and bizarre, not by achieving any honorable feat in the eyes of Viking Age Scandinavia.\n\nLoki alternately assists the gods and giants, depending on which actions are most amusing and advantageous to him at the time. During Ragnarök, when the gods and giants engage in their ultimate struggle and the cosmos is destroyed, Loki joins the battle on the side of the giants. He even becomes the captain of the ship Naglfar, the Nail Ship, which carries many giants to their battle with the gods. When the battle for the world occurs, he and the god Heimdall injure each other.\n\nLoki\'s primary attributes are intelligence and cunning. He rarely engages in physical combat and, therefore, does not carry weapons. He also lacks charms, clothing, or well-documented vehicles. Loki possesses a pair of magical shoes—Loki carries shoes that he uses to run through the air and on water. On one occasion, he borrowed Freya\'s magical feathered cloak, though he returned it shortly thereafter. Despite his lack of personal equipment, Loki has an exceptionally prominent role in providing for the other gods.\n\nLoki is a prominent shape-shifter among the gods. On various occasions, he takes the form of a salmon, a flea, a fly, and a mare. He also assumes human forms, like an old woman named Thökk who refused to weep for the fallen god Baldur.\n\nLoki is perhaps best known for his villainous role in The Death of Baldur. After the prophesied death of the beloved god Baldur, Baldur\'s mother, Frigg, obtained promises from every living creature not to harm her son. Well, almost all—no such oath was secured from mistletoe, which the gods considered too small and harmless to harm Baldur. Upon discovering this oversight, Loki carved a mistletoe spear, placed it in the hands of the blind god Hod, and ordered him to throw it at Baldur. Hod, unaware of the weapon\'s origin, complied, and Baldur was pierced and died. The god Hermod rode Sleipnir to the underworld and beseeched Hel to release Baldur, demonstrating how much he was loved by all living creatures. Hel responded that if that were true, it should be no trouble to force every creature in the world to weep for Baldur, and if this happened, the dead god would be freed from his grave. Every living creature did indeed weep for Baldur, with one exception: a frost giantess named Thökk (Thanks), who was almost certainly Loki in disguise. Thus, Baldur had to remain with Hel.\n\nFor his many transgressions against them, the gods eventually forged chains from the entrails of Loki\'s son, Narfi, and bound him to three rocks in a cave. A venomous serpent sat above him, dripping poison onto his body. Loki\'s seemingly devoted and loving wife, Sigyn, sat by his side with a bowl to catch the venom. However, when the bowl became full, she had to leave her husband\'s side to empty it. When this happened, the drops of venom that fell onto Loki caused him to wriggle in pain, and his writhing created earthquakes. In this state, he lay until he frees himself at Ragnarök</string>
    <string name="midgard">Midgard, the home of humans is at the center of the world and is right next to Asgard. Midgard and Asgard are connected by a rainbow bridge called the Bifrost. Midgard is also surrounded by a vast ocean.\n\n\n\nIn Norse mythology, the first humans to live in Midgard were Ask and Embla, they were created from trees by Odin and his two brothers after defeating Ymir. Odin knew that humans were very weak compared to gods, therefore he created a vast ocean in which there were giant snakes that protected humans.\n\n\n\nThe name Midgard (Middle Enclosure) has a double meaning. The first meaning of the word refers to the position of civilization amidst an otherwise wild world (jotunheim), which is reflected on the cosmological plane by Midgard being surrounded by the uninhabited wilderness of Jotunheim, an often hostile world of giants. This is similar to the way continents are surrounded by oceans.\n\n\n\nThe serpent Jormungand lives in the sea and surrounds terrestrial Midgard and the wilderness on its borders, and Aegir and Randwell in the depths of the same waters and claim the lives of unfortunate sailors. This vertical axis is represented by the world tree Yggdrasil, which holds Asgard in its upper branches, Midgard at the base of its trunk, and the underworld between its roots.</string>
    <string name="mimir">Mímir, (The Rememberer) is a very wise being and advisor to the gods. it is impossible to say whether he was considered an Aesir god or a giant.\n\n\nMimir\'s home appears to be a well called Mímisbrunnr, which may be identical to the Well of Urd. Odin sacrificed an eye to Mimir in exchange for a drink from Mimir\'s well in order to see the future.\n\n\nMimir was killed and beheaded by the Vanir during the Aesir-Vanir War. After seeing the severed head, Odin preserved it with a special potion and sang magical songs to preserve it. He consulted with the chief in times of need, and continued to provide unrivaled advice.</string>
    <string name="modimagni">In Norse mythology, Magni was the prodigious son of the Aesir god Thor and his lover, the jötunn Járnsaxa. Through his father he is the older half-brother of Móði and úrúðr, and through his mother the half-brother of Heimdallr.\n\n\nBoth Magni and Modi would survive Ragnarök, inheriting their father\'s legendary hammer, Mjölnir.\n\n\nThree-year-old Magni is said to be the only Aesir god strong enough to lift Thor\'s jötunn Hrungnir. As a reward for his power, Hrungnir\'s horse, Gullfaxi, was given to Magni by Thor.</string>
    <string name="muspelheim">Muspelheim is the southernmost region in the world of Norse mythology. Muspelheim is a hot place full of lava and fire.\n\n\nThe fire from Muspelheim and the ice from Niflheim met in the center of Ginnungagap and forged the giant Ymir, the first creature whose corpse eventually formed the world.\n\n\nThis place is the abode of giants and fire demons led by Surtr, the enemy of the gods.\n\n\nIn Ragnarok later, Surtr will go with a flaming sword in his hand and attack Asgard which then turns Asgard into hell.</string>
    <string name="nerthus">Nerthus was the goddess of the earth. Every year a festival is held where the goddess travels in a chariot pulled by two white heifers, accompanied by a priestess. No war is allowed during this activity. Even iron equipment was locked during the goddess\' journey. Every place the goddess passes will bring good luck.\n\n\nAt the end of the festival, the priest would guide the chariot to a sacred lake, where Nerthus bathed. His chariot was then covered with cloth. After a select few slaves bathed the goddess in the lake, the slaves were drowned as sacrifices to Nerthus.\n\n\nNerthus\' attributes also resemble those of his Celtic mythological counterparts, the Matres or Matrones, who were a group of mother goddesses famous on the Rhine.\n\n\nAlthough the cult of Nerthus appears to have ended in the 5th or 6th century, later tradition holds that he was identified with the god of Norse mythology, Njörd (Njord), who was the Vanir god of the wind and sea. Njörd is the masculine form of Nerthus. How Nerthus can experience sex change.\n\n\nNerthus may have been the nameless sister and wife of Njörd, in Norse mythology, who was the mother of Freyr and Freyja.</string>
    <string name="nidhogg">Nidhogg is the snake/dragon at the forefront of several snakes or dragons who live under the world tree Yggdrasil and eat its roots. This is extremely dangerous for the tree, which holds the Nine Worlds of the cosmos.\n\n\nNidhogg\'s actions had the intention of drawing the cosmos back into chaos, and he, along with his band of reptiles, can therefore certainly be classified among the giants (or, as they were called in pre-Christian times, the devourers).\n\n\nFrom here it makes sense that Nidhogg had an important role in Ragnarok, the destruction of the universe. This does appear to be the case.\n\n\nNidhogg is depicted flying out from beneath Yggdrasil during Ragnarok, perhaps to aid the giants\' cause.</string>
    <string name="niflheim">Niflheim is the darkest and coldest region in the world according to Norse mythology. Niflheim is in the northern region of Ginnungagap. The homeland of ancient darkness, cold, fog and ice. There is also the oldest well called Hvergelmir which is protected by a great dragon named Nidhug.\n\n\nIt is said that the well is the origin of all living things and the place where every living creature will return. Even so, in Niflheim no living creatures can live there because nothing can withstand the cold of Niflheim.\n\n\nthe first creature, the giant Ymir, was born when the ice from Niflheim and the fire from Muspelheim met in the middle of Ginnungagap, the chasm that once separated them.</string>
    <string name="njord">Njord is the god of the wind and sea in Norse mythology. It is also believed to be the god of wealth by sailors in the Viking era who always associated their wealth with the sea, because most of the Vikings\' wealth was obtained from sea catches. He is believed to have the ability to calm sea waters and extinguish fires, calm storms, help ships in difficulty navigate, and blow winds that bring good luck. Njord is associated with seafaring in the beliefs of the Vikings who were very rich and prosperous and were able to provide wealth in the form of land and other valuable objects to those who asked for their help.\n\n\nHe is also described as the protector of sailors and fishermen and the one who controls their fate\n\n\nGod Njord has a residence on the edge of the sea called Noathun (a stopover place for ships). He had two twins, Freyr and Freya and a twin sister, Nerthus, who was also his first wife.\n\n\nHe was the leader of the Vanir gods, especially during the war between the Vanir and the Aesir gods, who then exchanged himself for the Aesir as ransom for the Vanir prisoners of war.\n\n\nGod Njord is one of several gods who is said to have survived the Ragnarok event (the destruction of Asgard). In one story it is said that Njord married the giant Skadi, the daughter of a giant named Tjahzi. Skadi married Dewa Njord because of her own mistake. This story begins with the kidnapping of the banquet serving god (Dewa Idun) by Tjahzi who was then judged by the Aesir Gods, resulting in the death of the giant Tjahzi. Knowing this incident, Skadi plans to take revenge on the gods who are holding a party in Asgard by bringing one of the giant Tjahzi\'s arms as evidence.\n\n\nThere was a long struggle between the giant Skadi and the gods in the halls of Asgard. The dispute ended with a reconciliation that Skadi had the right to choose her future husband from among the gods present, after Skadi previously rejected the offer of compensation in the form of giving a wergild (golden treasure belonging to the god Odin). However, the condition that she has to fulfill is that Skadi must choose her future husband based on just looking at his lower legs. However, Skadi didn\'t get what she expected, namely choosing Dewa Baldr (the handsome son of God Odin) but instead chose Dewa Njord whose skin looked old and had a distinctive smell of salt and sea.\n\n\nThe gods Njord and Skadi lived together for a fairly short period of time. This is because God Njord prefers to live in his place on the shores of the sea which is warm and busy with the roar of the waves, while the giant Skadi still wants to live in his original place, Thrymheim (house of thunder), a place at the top of the mountains which is cold, dark and quiet. They had stayed in Thrymheim for 9 days but Dewa Njord could not enjoy the dark atmosphere and the roar of wolves, likewise when they tried to stay in Noathun for 9 days, Skadi was very disturbed by the chirping of birds and the heat of the sea shore, until finally they decided to separate.</string>
    <string name="nott">Nott is the personification of night. Nótt is listed as the daughter of a figure called Nörvi (with different spellings) and is associated with the horse Hrímfaxi, while the Prose Edda displays information about Nótt\'s ancestry, including her three marriages. Nótt\'s third marriage was to the god Dellingr and this produced their son Dagr, the personified day (although some manuscript variations list Jörð as Dellingr\'s wife and Dagr\'s mother instead). As a noun, the word nótt appears throughout the literature</string>
    <string name="odin">Odin is the highest and oldest god among the gods.\nOdin is depicted as a one-eyed old man. He gave one of his eyes in exchange for wisdom. Odin knows many secrets of the world. He has 2 crows named Huggin and Munnin. Huggin means mind. Munnin means memory. The two crows often fly around the world in search of news. They whispered the news into Odin\'s ear as they perched beside him. Odin also has a pair of wolves named Geri and Freki.\n\n\nOne of the most striking attributes of his appearance is his single, piercing eye. His other eye socket was empty – the eye he once held was sacrificed for wisdom.\n\n\nOn another occasion, Odin sacrificed himself by hanging from the world tree Yggdrasil for nine days and nine nights, accepting no food or drink. At the end of this ordeal, he saw the runes, an ancient Germanic alphabet that contained many of the greatest secrets.\n\n\nOdin reigns in Asgard, the land of the gods. However, he likes to travel in disguise so he can see the world as it really is. When disguised, Odin is said to take the form of a tall, tall man wearing a robe and hat. His distinctive feature is his other eye. Odin has many names in various regions. He is known as Blindr, the blind god. Odin is also known as Hoarr, the one-eyed. Baleyg, the fire eye, is also his nickname.\n\n\nOdin has a mainstay weapon, namely a javelin named Gungmir. The javelin can penetrate anything. When thrown, the javelin will always hit its target. He used this javelin during Ragnarok, the apocalypse of the gods in Norse mythology. Odin threw his javelin at Fenrir, a giant wolf who was about to devour him. The javelin disappeared inside the giant wolf\'s mouth. Likewise Odin. He was swallowed by Fenrir, the giant wolf.</string>
    <string name="odr">Odr is an obscure and rarely mentioned god.\nThe god Odr plays a completely passive role: once, Odr goes far away from the other gods. The purpose and reason for his departure were never stated.\n\n\nFreya looked for him in vain, and wept bitterly when he was not there\nFreya, Odr\'s wife, is almost indistinguishable from Odin\'s wife, Frigg. the names Odin and Odr are practically identical. Odin was exiled by the other gods for a long time, and Odr\'s absence certainly fits the occasion</string>
    <string name="ratatoskr">Ratatoskr is known as a mythical animal in Norse mythology. It is said that the name is taken from the Old Norse word which means drill tooth.\nThe form of this animal is described as a squirrel. He served as a message intermediary for the eagle perched at the top of the Yggdrasil tree and the Niohoggr snake at the base of the tree, precisely at one of the tree\'s three roots.</string>
    <string name="siff">Sif is a Norse goddess who is mentioned quite often in Old Norse literature, namely that she was the wife of the storm god Thor. The name seems to mean (relationship through marriage)\n\n\nShe was said to be the mother of the unknown god Ullr, whose unknown father turned out to be someone other than Thor.\n\n\nHe also plays a role in the story The Creation of Thor\'s Hammer, although here too, his role is completely passive. It is said here that Sif had beautiful golden hair, which was cut by the cunning trickster Loki one day when he found himself in a particularly mischievous mood. Thor, enraged, threatens to kill Loki, but Loki convinces the thunder god to spare his life on the condition that he finds more beautiful hair for Sif. Thor agrees, and Loki goes to get Sif new hair.\n\n\nOne of Thor\'s main roles in ancient Germanic religion was as a bringer of agricultural abundance.\n\n\nThe existence of Sif was specifically associated with vegetation on the surface of the earth, as indicated by the nature of its hair, also corroborated by the fact that a species of moss (Polytrichum aureum) was called haddr Sifjar (Sif\'s hair) in Old Norse.</string>
    <string name="skadi">Skadi is a giant and goddess in Norse mythology. The name is identical to the Old Norse noun skaði, danger,\n\n\nSkadi lives in the highest mountains, where the snow never melts. He was an avid hunter, and his bow, snowshoes, and skis were his most frequently mentioned attributes.\n\n\nShe was once married to the god Njord. However, their marriage failed; Njord couldn\'t stand the cold and gloomyness of the mountains, and Skadi couldn\'t stand the light and noise of Njord\'s house on the seashore, so the two went their separate ways.\n\n\nGiants (or, to use a word that better translates their Old Norse name, devourers) are mostly forces of darkness, cold, and death. Skadi fits this pattern, and seems to have a special association with winter. Her status as a goddess by marriage, however, together with the frequency of her historical cult, seems to suggest that she had a more benevolent attitude than most of her relatives, perhaps in the capacity of patron of winter subsistence activities.</string>
    <string name="skollhati">Skoll and Hati (or Hati Hrodvitnisson) are two giant wolves who chase two celestial bodies, namely the sun and the moon.(nott and dagr.)\n\n\nSkoll and Hati are the children of Fenrir, a giant wolf bound by the gods to prevent disaster.\n\n\nIt was predicted that Fenrir would eat the god Odin during Ragnarok.\nOne sign that Ragnarok will begin is that Skoll succeeded in eating the Sun, and Hati succeeded in swallowing the moon. After that the Nine Worlds will suffer a long winter. destruction of the cosmos, they catch their prey as heaven and earth darken and collapse.</string>
    <string name="surtr">Surt was a fire giant who led his kin into battle against the Aesir and Vanir gods during Ragnarok, the destruction of the cosmos. His particular fate is to kill the god Freyr and be killed by him in turn. He hails from Muspelheim, the southernmost region of heat and fire, bearing his weapon of choice in the form of a flaming sword, with which the world was leveled before sinking into the sea.\n\n\nSurt existed before chaos, namely the formation of the universe, no one knows for sure where surt was born.</string>
    <string name="svartalheim">Svartalfheim is the home of the dwarves. They live in dark rock caves. Hredmar is the king of the dwarves. Despite their small bodies, dwarves are endowed with many skills. The gods of Asgard have received many gifts from the dwarves, for example Odin\'s spear and Thor\'s hammer.\n\n\nThe dwarves are master blacksmiths and craftsmen who live underground. Therefore, Nidavellir or Svartalfheim might be considered a labyrinth, a complex of underground mines and forges.</string>
    <string name="thor">Thor is one of the most prominent figures in Norse mythology. He is a major god, although he reached the peak of his popularity among the Scandinavian people in the late Viking Age.\n\nThor, the muscular god of thunder, is the archetype of a loyal and honorable warrior, an ideal sought after by ordinary human warriors. He is the tireless defender of the Aesir gods and their stronghold, Asgard, from the disturbances of the giants.\nNo one is better suited for this task than Thor. His unwavering bravery and sense of duty are unshakable, and his physical strength is almost unmatched. He even possesses an unnamed strength belt (referred to as \"Megingjarðar\" in Old Norse) that doubles his power when he wears it. However, his most famous possession is his hammer, Mjöllnir. Rarely does he go anywhere without it. For the heathen people of Scandinavia, just as thunder is the embodiment of Thor, lightning is the manifestation of his hammer, which slays giants as he rides through the sky in a chariot pulled by goats. (Of course, they did not believe he physically rode a chariot pulled by goats—like other elements in Germanic mythology, this is a symbol used to express the unseen reality in which the material world is believed to be patterned.)\n\nThor\'s special enemy is Jormungand, the giant sea serpent that encircles Midgard, the world of human civilization. In one myth, he attempted to pull Jormungand out of the sea while on a fishing trip but was stopped only when his giant companion cut the fishing line out of fear. Thor and Jormungand eventually face each other during Ragnarok, where they both meet their end.\n\nConsidering his constant vigilance in protecting the pre-Christian northern European cosmos from the forces of chaos, destruction, and entropy represented by the giants, it is somewhat ironic that Thor himself is three-quarters giant. His father, Odin, is half-giant, and his mother, known by various names such as Jord (Old Norse for Earth), Hlöðyn, or Fjörgyn, is entirely of giant lineage. However, such mixed heritage is quite common among the gods, and it underscores how the relationship between the gods and giants, tense and full of conflict, cannot be reduced to mere enmity.\n\nHis activities in the divine realm are reflected in his activities in the human realm (Midgard), where he is invoked by those in need of protection, comfort, blessings, and the sanctification of places, objects, and events. Many surviving inscriptions call upon him to sanctify words and intentions, and he is the one called upon to bless marriages. This is preserved, among other places, in the story of Thor Disguised as a Bride. Early Icelandic settlers asked him to sanctify a plot of land before they built structures or planted crops.\n\nThor\'s hammer can be used for sanctification just as easily as it can be used for destruction—and, fundamentally, these two qualities are one and the same because any purification must involve the removal of hostile forces or elements. The blessing of marriages, for example, is done through his hammer. Perhaps the most striking example of this, however, is his ability to kill and eat the goats that pull his chariot, gather their bones in their skins, bless the skins with his hammer, and then revive the animals, healthy and whole, as they were before.\n\nFertility and Agriculture\nIn addition to his role as an exemplary warrior and the defender of social order and ambition, Thor also plays a significant role in promoting farming and fertility (something suggested by his blessings from the land on which the first Icelanders settled). This is another extension of his role as a sky god and is primarily associated with rain, which allows crops to grow. As the 11th-century German historian Adam of Bremen noted, Thor, they say, leads the air, which controls thunder and lightning, wind and rain, clear weather and crops. His rarely mentioned wife, Sif, is known for her golden hair above all, which is certainly a symbol of the fields of wheat.</string>
    <string name="tyr">Tyr is the Norse god of war, but also the god who, more than any other, presides over matters of law and justice. Its role in surviving Viking Age myths is relatively minor, and its status in the latter part of the Viking Age was probably minor as well. But this is not always the case. Another type of evidence shows us that Tyr was once one of the most important gods of the Norse and other Germanic peoples.\n\n\nWar, Law, and Justice\n\n\nTyr\'s role as one of the principal war gods of the Norse, along with Odin and Thor, the valkyrie Sigrdrifa instructed the human hero Sigurd to plead with Tyr for victory in battle. Loki insulted Tyr by saying that he could only stir people to discord, and could never reconcile them.\n\n\nTyr is far from just a god of war. In fact, his main role seems to be that of law enforcement and justice.</string>
    <string name="urd">The Urd Well is a well of destiny guarded by creatures called Norns. Norns are a group of three goddesses who control destiny. The goddesses are Urd, Verdandy, and Skuld. The Urd well is under the trunk/tree of yggdrasil\n\n  There is a story that tells that Odin once went to the well of Urd to obtain runes (the power to see the future). Odin fasted and hung himself on a tree, impaling himself with a spear for a week, it was the Norns who said there would be a Ragnarok apocalypse.</string>
    <string name="valkrie">It is symbolized in ancient books that the Valkyries are winged humans who carry staffs. Valkyries were considered gods because they were wise and usually helped Norse warriors in war. They are tasked with summoning the souls of selected deceased people to be brought to Valhalla to become Einherjar who will later help the gods when Ragnarok arrives.\n\n\nThe modern image of the valkyries as graceful and noble maidens who carry dead heroes to Valhalla. their love affairs were with human men and they assisted Odin in transporting his favorites among those killed in battle to Valhalla, where they would fight by his side. during Ragnarok.\n\n\nAs far as we know today, the Valkyries have always had such characteristics, but in pagan times they were much more evil. The meaning of their name, (slain elector,) refers not only to the choice of those who gain entry to Valhalla, but also the choice of those who die in battle and use evil magic to ensure that their preferences in this matter come to fruition. . Examples of Valkyries deciding who lives and who dies abound in the Eddas and sagas. The terrible side of the Valkyries is illustrated most clearly in Darraðarljóð, a poem contained in the Saga Njal. Here, twelve valkyries are seen before the Battle of Clontarf, sitting at looms and weaving the tragic fates of the warriors (an activity very reminiscent of the Norn). They use intestines for their twine, severed heads for weights, and swords and arrows for beaters, while chanting their intentions with ominous glee. The Saga of the Volsungs compares looking at a valkyrie to looking at fire.</string>
    <string name="vallhala">Vallhala was the hall where the god Odin housed the dead he deemed worthy to live with him. The bright, gold-like Valhalla was made of shields, and had spears for its rafters. Chairs made of breastplates surrounded the many banquet tables in the spacious hall.\nThe gates are guarded by wolves, and eagles fly above them.\n\n\nThe dead living in Valhalla, the einherjar, lived a life any Viking warrior would envy. All day long, they fought with each other, performing countless glorious deeds along the way. But every night, all their wounds were healed, and they recovered completely.\n\n\nThey were definitely very excited from all that fighting, and their dinner did not disappoint. Their meat comes from the boar Saehrimnir (Old Norse Sæhrímnir, which comes to life every time he is slaughtered and slaughtered. For their drink, they have mead that comes from the udders of the goat Heidrun (Old Norse Heiðrun. Thus, they enjoy a rich supply of food and drink endlessly delicious. They were waited on by the beautiful Valkyrie.\n\n\nBut the einherjar will not live this charmed life forever. The combat-skilled inhabitants of Valhalla are there at the will of Odin, who gathered them for the very selfish purpose of having them come to his aid in the fateful struggle against the wolf Fenrir during Ragnarok – a battle in which Odin and the einherjar were destined to lose by death.</string>
    <string name="vanaheim">Vanaheim (Old Norse Vanaheimr, Homeland of the Vanir) is one of the Nine Worlds located around the world tree Yggdrasil. As the name suggests, Vanaheim is the home of the Vanir gods.\n\n\nThe Vanir Gods are masters of magic and can predict the future. No one knows where Vanaheim is and no one knows what Vanaheim looks like. The three most known Vanir gods are Njord, Freya and Freyr.</string>
    <string name="ve">Ve is one of the ancient Scandinavian gods and, along with Odin and Vili, the son of the primordial pair of giants Bor and Bestla. The three brothers created heaven and earth from the slain body of the ancient creature Ymir and established the twelve realms. They also created Ask and Embla, the first human couple.</string>
    <string name="verd">It was the eagle that sat between the eyes of the nameless eagle perched atop the world tree Yggdrasil. Veðrfölnir is sometimes modernly anglicized as Vedrfolnir, Vedfolnir or Vethrfolnir.\n\n\nThe unnamed eagle, the squirrel ratatoskr carries messages between the unnamed eagle and Nidhöggr, the wyrm that resides under the world tree. they send messages mocking each other.</string>
    <string name="vili">In Scandinavian myth, one of the primordial gods, brother of Odin and Ve. The three of them were responsible for the creation of the universe, as well as the first humans.</string>
    <string name="ygg">In Norse mythology, Yggdrasil is the tree of life, a very large and sacred giant tree that connects the nine worlds in Norse cosmology. Yggdrasil is described as a tree that supports the universe. So, before being called Yggdrasil, this tree was also named Mimameidr by the Ancient Norse people, which means support of the universe. Sometimes called Lérað.\n\n\n\nOn its branches lie Ásgard, Vanaheim, and Álfheim. At its stem lies the human world called Midgard, around which Jötunheim is also located, and below it lies Nidhavellir which is also called Svartálfheim. Its three roots penetrate three worlds named Hel, Niflheim, and Muspelheim, although only the first world received the Yggdrasil spring.\nYggdrasil appears in the mythology of Ragnarök. In this mythology, only two humans managed to save themselves from Ragnarök, named Lif and Lifthrasir, who took refuge in a branch of Yggdrasil. Where they live off the dew and are protected.\n\n\n\nThere are several creatures living in the branches of Yggdrasil. Apart from Nidhoggr and several snakes, which gnaw at the roots., Ratatoskr, and a verdfornir eagle. The eagle and squirrel often take turns bothering Nidhog.\n\n\n\nMeanwhile the goat Heidrun lives on the roof of Valhalla, along with the stag Eikthyrnir. Heidrun likes to eat the new shoots growing from trees, and Eikthyrnir eats the leaves of Yggdrasil.\n\n\n\nHowever, Heidrun also produces a flow of honey into the great tub of Valhalla. This honey was used by knights who often trained for Ragnarok.\nBut in some parts, Yggdrasil and Odin are also considered the same figure.\n\n\n\nBecause it supports the world, Ygdrassil is protected by three old women called the Norn. They are described as Urd (past), Verdandi (present), and Skuld (future). The three Norns are also tasked with shaping time through weaving.\n\n\n\nYggdrassil will also be the place where the last two humans—Lif and Lifthrasir—can take refuge. It is in this protection that, when all the chaos ends, they will become Ask and Embla to restart the creation of humanity.</string>
    <string name="ymirfight">The first of the early giants was known as Ymir (groaner). The frost giants called him Aurgelmir (gravel caller). Ymir was the first creature created in the world. Ymir is the ancestor of the ice giants. Ice giants are born from the sweat of his armpits.\n\n\nYmir was the father of an unnamed six-armed giant who was nourished by a giant cow named Audumla. Audumla itself obtains food by licking rocks. The rocks were licked until they formed humans and became an early god named Buri. Buri was the father of another early god (or giant), namely Bor. Bor and Bestla became the parents of three gods, namely Odin, Vili and Ve.\n\n\nOdin and his brothers, Vili and Ve, killed Ymir. They use their bodies to create the world. his skull became the sky and his eyebrows became Midgard, the home of humanity.</string>
    <string name="ymir">YMIR is a hermaphroditic giant and the first creature to appear in Norse creation myths. As the first giant, he was the ancestor of all the other giants – and, since almost all the gods were partly descended from giants, he was also their ancestor.\n\n\nYmir was born when the fire of Muspelheim and the ice of Niflheim met in the Ginnungagap ravine. Ymir was suckled by the cow Audhumla for food. While he slept, several other giants were conceived asexually in Ymir\'s hermaphroditic body, and spontaneously emerged from his feet and sweat from his armpits.\n\n\nAudhumla received his food from a salt lick, and as he licked, a creature named Buri, the first Aesir god, was freed from within the salt. She produced a son, Borr, who mated with Bestla, one of Ymir\'s descendants. From their union came Odin, chief of the Aesir, and his two brothers, Vili and Ve.\n\n\nIt was these brothers who later killed Ymir and formed the cosmos from her corpse.\n\n\nThematically, Ymir is the personification of the chaos before creation, which is also depicted as Ginnungagap\'s impersonal emptiness. Both Ymir and Ginnungagap are ways of talking about unlimited potential that is not yet actualized, that is not yet a particular thing that we find in the world around us. This is why the Vikings described it as a void (as did countless others; consider the darkness on the surface of the sea from the first chapter of the Book of Genesis, for example). This is nothingness. Nevertheless, it contains basic things from which the gods can make true things – in this case, the primary material is Ymir\'s body, which the gods tore apart to make the elements.\n\n\nIt is fitting for Ymir to be the ancestor of the giants, as this is a common role for giants in Norse myth. They are a formless force of chaos, always threatening to corrupt and ultimately overturn the order created by the gods (and in Ragnarok, they succeed). But giants are more than just a destructive force.</string>
    <string name="ttgaplikasi">ABOUT</string>
    <string name="tentang">Before the Norse people (aka Germanic Vikings) converted to Christianity during the Middle Ages, they had a vibrant native pagan religion that was as beautiful as the Norse landscape with which it is closely associated. The core of that religion was what we now call “Norse mythology:” a collection of religious stories that gave meaning to Viking life. This myth tells the story of gods and goddesses. And in this application we summarize it and provide information about the Norse gods and goddesses which is packaged concisely and easy to understand, which comes from ancient Norse sources.</string>
    <string name="aplikasilain">OTHER APP</string>
</resources>